hey everybody welcome to this a2 English
listening practice video you can use
this video to practice your listening
and comprehension as I speak you ready
so today I'm gonna talk about the
seasons of course there are four main
seasons that exist spring summer fall
and winter in English the fall season is
also called autumn so you can hear some
people say fall and other people say
autumn let's talk about some of the
differences between the four seasons
spring is universally known as the
season that brings life this is the time
of year when the flowers bloom and the
trees fill with new leaves in some
regions spring is a really beautiful
season but in other places spring isn't
so exciting
for example if you live in the northern
regions of the US spring is usually a
really beautiful time of year but if you
live in other parts of the US there
isn't much difference between spring and
the other seasons when I lived in Oregon
I saw a real spring for the first time
the trees turned green pink and purple
and the whole landscape looked different
but in the other cities where I've lived
this type of spring season doesn't exist
spring is also the season when the days
get longer because most countries start
daylight savings time at the beginning
of spring this is my favorite thing
about the season okay now let's talk
about summer this is my favorite season
because I love the Sun and I love long
days of course in some places summer can
be uncomfortable because of the heat in
certain cities the temperature in the
summer can be 40 or even 45 degrees
Celsius this is too hot even for me I
can handle hot weather but if it's
hotter than 40 degrees that's a little
too much summer is usually kids favorite
season too because they have summer
break or summer vacation when I was
young everyone would get so excited in
June
because it was the last month of school
we would get about two and a half months
of break and it was great summer is also
the season when many people take family
vacations and travel in my opinion
summer is the best season of them all
okay now let's talk about fall or autumn
fall is similar to spring in that some
places don't really have this season but
if you go to a region that does have
this season you'll see some amazing
colors for example when I lived in
Oregon fall was a distinct season around
the end of September the leaves on the
trees would change color and become red
orange and yellow if you've never seen
this before I recommend that you take a
trip to a region that has this season
it's such a cool experience to see the
colors and of course leaves fall down
from the trees so there are leaves
everywhere on the ground that means that
when you walk there are always leaves
crunching under your feet but in most of
the cities where I've lived there is no
real fall season all right lastly let's
talk about winter for many people this
is the worst season because it's really
cold if you live in a cold country
winter lasts for a really long time this
brings a lot of problems and hard work
in the cities where I've lived though
winter is mild in Southern California
and Mexico the temperature doesn't get
very low and it doesn't snow so I've
never experienced a true winter before
and I'm ok with that
I think winter can also be beautiful if
there's snow and there are plenty of fun
winter activities that you can only do
in the snow like skiing and snowboarding
so winter can be either miserable or
great depending on who you are and where
you are ok that's all for today leave a
comment and tell me what your favorite
season is I'll see you next time
[Music]
[Applause]